A Guide to the Herbert E. Harris II Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10466
Herbert E. Harris II Papers ca. 1974-1981
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10466
43000 items
Herbert E. Harris II
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research, except for Series VI: Restrcited File. Permission to access this series must be obtained from Mr. Harris; contact Department for further information.
Acquisition Information
The Harris Papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Mr. Herbert E. Harris II of Washington, D. C., on 1 July 1981.
Biographical Sketch
Herbert E. Harris II was born in Kansas City, Missouri, on April 14, 1926. He did his undergraduate work at Missouri Valley College, Rockhurst College, and the University of Notre Dame, where he received a Bachelor of Arts degrees. Harris earned a law degree from Georgetown University Law School but his education was interrupted in 1942 when he served as an U. S. naval officer during World War II. He settled in Fairfax County in 1956 and became involved in civic affairs; in 1967 he made his first campaign for public office and was elected to the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors.
He was involved in concerns beyond northern Virginia; as an attorney specializing in international trade he helped draft America's first Food for Peace law in 1955. Seven years later, he drafted parts of President John F. Kennedy's Trade Expansion Act of 1962. In 1974 Harris was elected to Congress from Virginia's Eighth District as the state's first Catholic congressman. Harris served on the House Post Office and Civil Service committees and the House's District of Columbia committee. He chaired the House Subcommittees on the Bicentennial, Environment, and International Community during his first term. Harris was also an active member of the Environmental Study Conference and a founders of the Caucus of New Democratic House Members.
Scope and Content
The Herbert E. Harris(1926-) papers, ca. 1974-1981, consist of ca. 43,000 items (107 Hollinger boxes, ca. 37 cubic feet), correspondence, newsletters, photographs notes, printed matter and miscellaneous materials resulting from Harris's tenure as a member of the U. S. House of Representatives during the 94th, 95th, and 96th Congresses, 1975-1981, representing the Eighth District of Virginia. These papers relate to his years in office until his defeat in his bid for reelection in November 1980. There is very little material specifically related to his campaigns for public office, and other miscellaneous activities.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence between Harris and his constituents, including exchanges of political ideas and appeals for information or assistance. These provide some insight into the legislative activities of Harris as a congressman. One such example was his successful attempt to expand the boundaries of the Manassas National Battlefield Park and his efforts toward the creation of a Tenants' Tax Justice bill.
Organization
The collection comprises six series. Series I, Public Relations; Series II, Correspondence; Series III, Legislation Files (correspondence and all other material relating to legislative measures were removed from other areas of the collection and consolidated as subseries within Series III); Series IV, Photographs; Series V, Overwise; and Series VI, Restricted Files, comprised of restricted material such as job applications, resumes, and salary information. Throughout the various series Harris's original filing system has been retained with some modifications. Folders are arranged chronologically or alphabetically within each series. The original internal order and titles of select folders has been retained.
Series I: Public Relations Materials: This series' folders include Harris press releases, statements,
Journal Messenger
columns, special reports, and newsletters. This series has been divided into four sections:
A. Press Release (Boxes 1-8): This material was retained in its original folders and folder headings are arranged chronologically. These files generally do not provide substantive information about Harris's congressional activities or his views about legislation. They provide a brief overview of his position on various contemporary subjects.
B. Statements (Boxes 8-9): These were retained in their original folders and arranged chronologically. They contain prepared statements for inclusion in the
Congressional Record
"Dear Colleague" letters, memoranda, correspondence and some press releases.
C.
Journal Messenger
Columns (Box 10): These folders are arranged by year for Harris's column, "The Congressional Mail Bag." This weekly column featured sampling of constituent letters to Harris and his responses to them. These folders contain the unedited text of the columns, from the first one for the week of September 15, 1975 until August 8, 1980. In the front of several folders are indexes to the topic covered during the specific year.
D. Special Reports and Newsletters (Box 11): These are in their original folders and are arranged chronologically. Each folder contains a finished report or newsletter with various drafts. The nature of a particular report or newsletter is indicated in the original folder headings. Reports or newsletters either deal primarily with a particular topic or are directed toward a specific constituency.
Series II: Correspondence: This series contains constituent mail, as well as correspondence with other legislators and government officials. Certain folders are arranged in reverse chronological order under a subseries A of the same name (Boxes 12-19); in subseries B, "Topical Correspondence" (Boxes 20-66); or as subseries C, "Alphabetical Correspondence" (Boxes 67-70).
Series III: Legislation Files: This series contains Harris's legislative activities as a member of the 94th, 95th and 96th Congresses, and is arranged into three general categories: Legislative Information Files, Subject Files, and Chronological Legislative Files. The Legislative Files are divided into five subseries:
A. Legislative Information Files: These contain folders for Harris-sponsored legislation; empty ones are retained. House bills are filed first, in numerical order, followed by resolutions and joint resolutions (Boxes 71-81).
B. Subject Files: These contain reports, "Dear Colleague" letters, memos, statements, and correspondence about various legislative topics. Subject folders differ from the legislative files in that the former are arranged only by general topics while each folder in the Legislative Information Files relates specifically to a particular bill (Boxes 82-99).
C. Chronological Legislative Files: These files are self-explanatory; furthermore, they pertain to proposed or pending legislation but unlike subseries B (Subject Files) it is a miscellaneous grouping of materials (Box 100).
D. Manassas National Battlefield Park Bill: Folders related to this legislation were transferred from throughout the collection and filed in this subseries for researcher convenience. It includes correspondence, and thanks to this measure the boundaries of the park were expanded by 1700 acres in order to protect it from encroaching commercial development (Boxes 101-104).
E. Tenants' Tax Justice Bill: This folders were pulled from the collection for consolidation in this subseries. This bill sought to allow tenants to claim a tax deduction for that part of their rent which paid local property taxes, rather than allowing the tax deduction solely for the owners of rental units (Box 104).
Series IV: Photographs File: Self-explanatory (Box 104).
Series V: Oversize: Most of these items (in Oversize box M-3) are maps pertaining to the Manassas National Battlefield Park bill.
Series VI: Restricted File: Materials such as job applications, resumes, and salary information are restricted. No access is allowed without the written consent of Mr. Harris (Boxes 105-107).
Container List
- Series I: Public Relations Material
  - Subseries A: Press Releases
    - Typed List of all Press Releases, Statements, Special Reports & Newsletters (in Boxes 1-11), n.d. (Box Box 1)
    - Press Releases, 1974 Dec 23-1975 Dec 19; (49 folders) (Box Box 1)
    - Press Releases, 1976; (51 folders) (Box Box 2)
    - Press Releases, 1977 Jan-Aug; (46 folders) (Box Box 3)
    - Press Releases, 1977 Sep-1978 Oct; (51 folders) (Box Box 4)
    - Press Releases, 1979 Jan-Jun; (41 folders) (Box Box 5)
    - Press Releases, 1979 Jul-Dec; (37 folders) (Box Box 6)
    - Press Releases, 1980 Jan-Jun; (53 folders) (Box Box 7)
    - Press Releases, 1980 Jul-Nov; (39 folders) (Box Box 8)
  - Subseries B: Statements
    - Statements, 1975 Jan-Aug; (13 folders) (Box Box 8)
    - Statements, 1975 Sep-1976 Nov; (16 folders) (Box Box 9)
  - Subseries C: Journal Messenger Columns
    - Journal Messenger Columns, 1975-1980; (6 folders) (Box Box 10)
  - Subseries D: Special Reports & Newsletters
    - Special Reports and Newsletters, 1975-1980; (55 folders) (Box Box 11)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Subseries A: Reverse Chronological
    - Correspondence, 1975 Jan-Oct; (3 folders) (Box Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1975 Oct-Nov; (4 folders) (Box Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1975 Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 14)
    - Correspondence, 1976 Jan-Feb 10; (4 folders) (Box Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1976 Feb 11-Mar 15; (4 folders) (Box Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 1976 Mar 16-Apr 8; (3 folders) (Box Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1976 Apr 9-30; (3 folders) (Box Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1976 May-Jul; (4 folders) (Box Box 19)
  - Subseries B: Topical Correspondence
    - Agriculture, 1975 (Box Box 20)
    - Civil Rights, 1975 (Box Box 20)
    - Civil Service, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 20)
    - Civil Service, 1975 (Box Box 21)
    - Commerce, 1975; (3 folders) (Box Box 21)
    - Commerce, 1975 (Box Box 22)
    - Congress, U.S., 1975; (4 folders) (Box Box 22)
    - Congress, U.S., 1975 (Box Box 23)
    - Crime, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 23)
    - Defense Affairs, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 23)
    - Defense Affairs, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 24)
    - Economics, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 24)
    - Education, 1975 (Box Box 24)
    - Education, 1975 (Box Box 25)
    - Environment, 1975 (Box Box 25)
    - Energy, 1975; (4 folders) (Box Box 25)
    - Environment, 1975 (Box Box 26)
    - Executive Branch, 1975 (Box Box 26)
    - Finance, 1975 (Box Box 26)
    - Foreign Relations, 1975 (Box Box 26)
    - General, 1975; (3 folders) (Box Box 27)
    - Gratuities - Thank You's Received, 1975 (Box Box 27)
    - Gratuities - Thank You's Sent, 1974 Nov 22-1975 Feb 14; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 27)
    - Gratuities - Thank You's Sent, 1975 Feb-Sep; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 28)
    - Health and Welfare, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 28)
    - Housing & Urban Development, 1975; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 28)
    - Housing & Urban Development, 1975; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 29)
    - Immigration & Naturalization, 1975 (Box Box 29)
    - Indian Affairs, 1975 (Box Box 29)
    - Insurance & Retirement, 1975 (Box Box 29)
    - Judiciary, 1975 (Box Box 29)
    - Labor, 1975; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 29)
    - Labor, 1975; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 30)
    - Natural Resources, 1975 (Box Box 30)
    - Office of the President, 1975 (Box Box 30)
    - Parks and Recreation, 1975 (Box Box 30)
    - Political Affairs, 1975 (Box Box 30)
    - Postal Service, 1975 (Box Box 31)
    - Press, 1975 (Box Box 31)
    - Public Works, 1975 (Box Box 31)
    - Referrals, 1975 (Box Box 31)
    - Requests for Information, 1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 32)
    - Small Business, 1975 (Box Box 32)
    - Social Security, 1975 (Box Box 32)
    - Taxes, 1975; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 32)
    - Taxes, 1975; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 33)
    - Trade, 1975 (Box Box 33)
    - Transportation, 1975; (3 folders) (Box Box 33)
    - Unacknowledged Correspondence, 1975 (Box Box 33)
    - Veterans/ Servicemen, 1975 (Box Box 33)
    - Virginia's Eighth Congressional District, 1975; (4 folders) (Box Box 34)
    - Virginia State Affairs, 1975; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 34)
    - Virginia State Affairs, 1975; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 35)
    - Agriculture, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Appropriations, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Civil Rights, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Civil Service, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Civil Service - Retirement and Insurance, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Commerce, 1976 (Box Box 35)
    - Congress, U.S., 1976; (3 folders) (Box Box 36)
    - Crime, 1976 (Box Box 36)
    - Defense Affairs, 1976 (Box Box 36)
    - Economics, 1976 (Box Box 36)
    - Education, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - Energy, 1976; (2 folders) (Box Box 37)
    - Environment, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - Executive Branch, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - Finance, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - Foreign Relations, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - General - Questionnaires, 1976 (Box Box 37)
    - General, 1976; (3 folders) (Box Box 38)
    - General - Courtesy Correspondence, 1976 (Box Box 38)
    - Health and Welfare, 1976 (Box Box 38)
    - Health and Welfare, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Housing and Urban Development, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Immigration and Naturalization, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Indian Affairs, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Insurance and Retirement, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Judiciary, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Labor, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Natural Resources, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Office of the President, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Parks and Recreation, 1976 (Box Box 39)
    - Political Affairs, 1976; (2 folders of 4 folders) (Box Box 39)
    - Political Affairs, 1976; (3 and 4 of 4 folders) (Box Box 40)
    - Postal Service, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Press, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Public Activities, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Public Works, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Small Business, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Social Security, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Specials, 1976 (Box Box 40)
    - Specials - Inauguration, 1976-1977 (Box Box 41)
    - Taxes, 1976; (2 folders) (Box Box 41)
    - Transportation, 1976; (2 folders) (Box Box 41)
    - Treasury, U.S., 1976 (Box Box 41)
    - Veterans/ Servicemen, 1976 (Box Box 41)
    - Virginia State Affairs, 1976; (folder 1 of 2 folders) (Box Box 41)
    - Virginia State Affairs, 1976; (folder 2 of 2 folders) (Box Box 42)
    - Virginia's 8th Congressional District, 1976; (5 folders of 6 folders) (Box Box 42)
    - Virginia's 8th Congressional District, 1976; (folder 6 of 6 folders) (Box Box 43)
    - Civil Service, 1977; (folder 4 of 5 folders) (Box Box 43)
    - Civil Service, 1977; (folder 5 of 5 folders) (Box Box 44)
    - Commerce, 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Congress, U.S., 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Crime, 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Defense, 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Education, 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Energy, 1977 (Box Box 44)
    - Environment, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - General, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - Health and Welfare, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - Immigration, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - International Relations, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - Judiciary, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box Box 45)
    - Postal Service, 1977; (2 folders) (Box Box 45)
    - Public Works, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Social Security, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Taxes, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Transportation, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Veteran Affairs, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Virginia Eighth Congressional District, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Women, 1977 (Box Box 46)
    - Agriculture, 1978 (Box Box 46)
    - Armed Services, 1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 46)
    - Banking/ Finance/ Urban Affairs, 1978 (Box Box 46)
    - Civil Rights, 1978 (Box Box 46)
    - Commerce, 1978 (Box Box 46)
    - Crime, 1978 (Box Box 47)
    - Defense, 1978 (Box Box 47)
    - Economics, 1978 (Box Box 47)
    - Education, 1978 (Box Box 47)
    - Energy, 1978 (Box Box 47)
    - Environment, 1978; (folder 1 of 3 folders) (Box Box 47)
    - Environment, 1978; (folder 2 and 3 of 3 folders) (Box Box 48)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978 (Box Box 48)
    - Ethics and Congressional Reform, 1978 (Box Box 48)
    - General, 1978 (Box Box 48)
    - Health and Welfare, 1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 49)
    - Housing and Urban Development, 1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 49)
    - Immigration, 1978 (Box Box 49)
    - Indian Affairs, 1978 (Box Box 49)
    - Insurance and Retirement, 1978 (Box Box 49)
    - Interior, 1978 (Box Box 49)
    - International Relations, 1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 50)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1978 (Box Box 50)
    - Judiciary, 1978; (3 folders) (Box Box 50)
    - Labor, 1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 51)
    - Legislative Correspondence - "Multi"-Issue, 1978 (Box Box 51)
    - Merchant Marine and Fisheries, 1978 (Box Box 51)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box Box 51)
    - Natural Resources, 1978 (Box Box 51)
    - Post Office and Civil Service, 1978; (folder 1 of 5 folders) (Box Box 51)
    - Post Office and Civil Service, 1978; (folders 2-5 of 5 folders) (Box Box 52)
    - Small Business, 1978 (Box Box 52)
    - Social Security, 1978 (Box Box 53)
    - Taxes, 1978; (4 folders) (Box Box 53)
    - Trade, 1978 (Box Box 53)
    - Transportation, 1978 (Box Box 54)
    - Virginia Eighth Congressional District, 1978 (Box Box 54)
    - Agriculture, 1979-1980 (Box Box 54)
    - Appropriations, 1979-1980 (Box Box 54)
    - Armed Services, 1979-1980; (folders 1-3 of 4 folders) (Box Box 54)
    - Armed Services, 1979-1980; (folder 4 of 4 folders) (Box Box 55)
    - Banking, 1979-1980; (2 folders) (Box Box 55)
    - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box Box 55)
    - Congratulations, 1979-1980 (Box Box 55)
    - District of Columbia, 1979-1980 (Box Box 55)
    - Education and Labor, 1979-1980; (folders 1-2 of 7 folders) (Box Box 55)
    - Education and Labor, 1979-1980; (folders 3-7 of 7 folders) (Box Box 56)
    - Energy, 1979-1980 (Box Box 56)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1979-1980; (4 folders) (Box Box 57)
    - Government Operations, 1979-1980 (Box Box 58)
    - Health and Welfare, 1979-1980 (Box Box 58)
    - House Administration, 1979-1980 (Box Box 58)
    - Housing and Urban Development, 1979-1980 (Box Box 58)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1979-1980; (folders 1-2 of 20 folders) (Box Box 58)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1979-1980; (folders 3-7 of 20 folders) (Box Box 59)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1979-1980; (folders 8-13 of 20 folders) (Box Box 60)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1979-1980; (folders 14-18 of 20 folders) (Box Box 61)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1979-1980; (folders 19-20 of 20 folders) (Box Box 62)
    - Interior and Insular Affairs, 1979-1980; (2 folders) (Box Box 62)
    - Judiciary/ General, 1979-1980 (Box Box 62)
    - Judiciary/ Abortion, 1979-1980 (Box Box 63)
    - Judiciary, 1979-1980; (3 folders) (Box Box 63)
    - Merchant Marine and Fisheries, 1979-1980 (Box Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980; (folder 1 of 4 folders) (Box Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980; (folder 2-4 of 4 folders) (Box Box 64)
    - Post Office and Civil Services, 1979-1980; (2 folders) (Box Box 64)
    - Public Works and Transportation, 1979-1980; (6 folders) (Box Box 65)
    - Small Business, 1979-1980 (Box Box 65)
    - Standards of Official Conduct, 1979-1980 (Box Box 65)
    - Thank You, 1979-1980 (Box Box 66)
    - Veterans Affairs, 1979-1980 (Box Box 66)
    - Ways and Means, 1979-1980; (5 folders) (Box Box 66)
  - Subseries C: Alphabetical Correspondence
    - "A", 1979-1980 (Box Box 67)
    - "B", 1979-1980; (2 folders) (Box Box 67)
    - "C", 1979-1980; (2 folders) (Box Box 67)
    - "D", 1979-1980 (Box Box 68)
    - "E" and "F", 1979-1980 (Box Box 68)
    - "G", 1979-1980 (Box Box 68)
    - "H", 1979-1980 (Box Box 68)
    - "I" and "J", 1979-1980 (Box Box 69)
    - "K", 1979-1980 (Box Box 69)
    - "L", 1979-1980 (Box Box 69)
    - "M", 1979-1980 (Box Box 69)
    - "Mc", "N", and "O", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
    - "P" and "Q", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
    - "R", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
    - "S", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
    - "T", "U", and "V", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
    - "W", "Y", and "Z", 1979-1980 (Box Box 70)
- Series III: Legislation Files
  - Subseries A: Legislative Information Files
    - HR 609: Safety and Health (O.S.H.A.) (Box Box 71)
    - HR 1330: Require Federal Employees to file notice of gifts with Federal Registrar (Box Box 71)
    - HR 19; HR 1769: To stop the President from levying a tax on oil imports (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2446: Reduce Income taxes and remove tax preferences for oil and gas producers (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2446: Tax Bill, (2 folders) (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2559: To increase federal executives pay & cost of living increases (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2684: Financial Disclosure (personal) to promote public confidence (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2787: Provide for a National Student financial assistance data bank (Box Box 71)
    - HR 2966: The Child and Family Services Act (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3167; HR 4165: Increase amount of outside earnings to $3600 in Social Security Act (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3582: State Conservation Publications shall qualify for second-class mail (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3590: To create a Center for Prevention & Control of Rape (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3788: Requires individuals to file statements concerning income (Financial Disclosure Act) (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3838: Admission to the Service Academies be made non- discriminatory (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3906: Prohibit President from increasing the price of crude oil more $1 a barrel (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3934: Repeal Hatch Act to allow political participation and to stop harassment (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3991: Improve post-secondary vocational education programs (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3992: Amend Vocational Education Act of 1963 (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3993: Provide career guidance & counseling programs for state and local educational agencies (Box Box 71)
    - HR 7053; HR 4260: To eliminate the annuity deduction to provide survivor annuity (Box Box 71)
    - HR 4342: To establish the Land Use and Resource Conservation Act of 1975 (Box Box 71)
    - HR 3944; HR 4380: Imported Petroleum made available for purchase only to U.S. after 9/1/75 (Box Box 71)
    - HR 4551: To require retail unit prices of consumer commodities (Box Box 71)
    - HR 4619: Finance solar heating and cooling systems, low interest Federal loans (Box Box 71)
    - HR 4621: Include certain state workers in the computation of services (Box Box 71)
    - Retirement and Benefits - State Credit, (2 folders) (Box Box 71)
    - HR 4624: Unlawful employment practice to discriminate against physically disabled (Box Box 72)
    - HR 4729: A tax on automobiles based on its fuel consumption rate, disclosure (Box Box 72)
    - HR 4966; HR4913-4: Social Security benefits not returned for entire month recipient dies (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5023: Collective bargaining representative of Postal Employees (HR 7183) (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5091: Establishment of folklife center at Library of Congress (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5172: To establish a National Energy & Conservation Corporation (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5212: Amend Layton Act prohibit concentration in energy (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5524: To establish a temporary price on wage board (Box Box 72)
    - HR 15 (5613): Public Disclosure Lobbying Act of 1975 (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5622: Democratic Caucus Resolution & Moffett Resolution defeating oil Decontrol (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5691: Require Sec. of Navy to extract petroleum from naval petroleum reserves (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5743: To amend Social Security Act for prompt payment of Social Security Check (Box Box 72)
    - HR 5746: Oil & Gas from federal lands produced by private persons under contract with U.S. (Box Box 72)